Guide to the Harper Theater Dance Festival Records, 1961-1992
American Dance Festival Archives
- Company Files, 1964-1992, undated, (2 Boxes)
  - Festival Performers, 1962-1979, undated
    - Lewitzky, Bella (Box 5)
    - Lewitzky, Bella (Box 5)
    - Lewitzky, Bella: Press (Box 5)
    - Lewitzky, Bella: Press (Box 5)
    - Lewitzky, Bella: Posters, undated (Box 10)
      Non-Harper Theater Dance Festival posters (7)
    - Limón, José: Press (Box 5)
    - Limón, José: Press (Box 5)
    - Louis, Murray (Box 5)
    - Louis, Murray (Box 5)
    - Louis, Murray: Press (Box 5)
    - Louis, Murray: Press (Box 5)
    - Nagrin, Daniel (Box 5)
    - Nagrin, Daniel: Press (Box 5)
    - Nagrin, Daniel: Posters, undated (Box 10)
      Non-Harper Theater Dance Festival poster
    - Najan, Nala (Box 5)
    - Najan, Nala: Press (Box 5)
    - Nikolais and Murray (Box 5)
    - Nikolais, Alwin (Box 5)
    - Nikolais, Alwin: Press (Box 5)
    - Nikolais, Alwin: Press (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Ballet Company (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Ballet Company: Press (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania Ballet Company: Press (Box 5)
    - Pilobolus Dance Theatre (Box 5)
    - Pilobolus Dance Theatre: Press (Box 5)
    - Pilobolus Dance Theatre: Press (Box 5)
    - Pilobolus Dance Theatre: Posters, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Sokolow, Anna (Box 5)
    - Sokolow, Anna: Press (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Paul (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Paul (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Paul: Press (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Paul: Press (Box 5)
    - Tetley, Glen: Press (Box 5)
    - Tetley, Glen: Press (Box 5)
    - Tetley, Glen: Posters, undated (Box 10)
    - Villella, Edward: Press (Box 5)
  - Non-Festival Performers, 1962-1979, undated
    The Non-Festival Performers sub-series is arranged alphabetically by performer. Records include posters, programs, articles, and reviews of non-Festival performances, as well as general press kits.
    - Alenikoff, Frances (Box 5)
    - AllNations (Box 5)
    - Aman Folk Ensemble (Box 5)
    - American Ballet Theater (Box 5)
    - American Mime Theatre (Box 5)
    - Anthony, Mary (Box 5)
    - Art Services (Box 5)
    - Ballet Center of Buffalo (Box 5)
    - Ballet School of Lyric Opera (Box 5)
    - Bethune, Zina (Box 5)
    - Bettis, Valerie (Box 5)
    - Bhaskar (Box 5)
    - Boatright, Helen (Box 5)
    - Boutilier, Joy (Box 5)
    - Bowden, Sally (Box 5)
    - Brockport Resident Dance Company (Box 5)
    - Brown, Trisha (Box 5)
    - Chamber Ballet (Box 5)
    - Chicago Ballet (Box 5)
    - Chicago Ballet (Box 5)
    - Contemporary Dance System (Box 5)
    - Croll, Tina (Box 5)
    - Cowles, Peggy (Box 5)
    - Dance Concert Society (Box 6)
    - Dancers (Box 6)
    - Dance Repertory Company (Box 6)
    - Dance Theater of Harlem (Box 6)
    - Dance Theater of Harlem: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Dance Theatre of the Southwest (Box 6)
    - Dance Theater Workshop (Box 6)
    - Dance Theater Workshop (Box 6)
    - Dance Theater Workshop: Presenter (Box 6)
      Mailer
    - DTW (Box 6)
    - Dehn, Mura (Box 6)
    - Directional Concepts Theatre Foundation (Box 6)
    - Directional Concepts (Box 6)
    - Directional Concepts (Box 6)
    - Duncan, Jeff (Box 6)
    - Eglewsky Ballet Company (Box 6)
    - Eiko and Koma (Box 6)
    - Elgin Dance Film Festival (Box 6)
    - Elgin Dance Film Festival (Box 6)
    - The Ensemble (Box 6)
    - Entre Six (Box 6)
    - Fairmont Center Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Feld, Eliot (Box 6)
    - Feld, Eliot: Press (Box 6)
    - First Chamber Dance Company (Box 6)
    - Foreman, Laura (Box 6)
    - Frankel, Emily (Box 6)
    - Garrard, Mimi (Box 6)
    - Garrard, Mimi (Box 6)
    - Graham, Martha (Box 6)
    - Graham, Martha: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Graham, Martha: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Grimmer, Margot (Box 6)
    - Groupe de la Place Royale (Box 6)
    - Hall, Arthur (Box 6)
    - Hall, Joel (Box 6)
    - Harbinger (Box 6)
    - Harkness Ballet: Press (Box 6)
    - Harkness Ballet: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Hartford Ballet (Box 6)
    - Hartford Ballet (Box 6)
    - Hauser, Nancy (Box 6)
    - Hauser, Nancy (Box 6)
    - Herbert H. Lehman College (Box 6)
      Program
    - Hi Enterprises (Box 6)
    - Hi Enterprises (Box 6)
    - Hi Enterprises (Box 6)
    - Hirabayashi, Kazuko (Box 6)
    - Holmes, James (Box 6)
    - Holmes, Joséph (Box 6)
    - Holmes, Joséph (Box 6)
      Mixed public relations records programs
    - Houston Ballet (Box 6)
    - Hoving, Lucas (Box 6)
    - Mel Howard Productions Inc. (Box 6)
    - Hubbard Street Dance Company (Box 6)
    - Hubbard Street Dance (Box 6)
    - Indrani (Box 6)
    - International Company Press (Box 6)
    - Janislawski, Mimi (Box 6)
    - Jones, Betty (Box 6)
    - Jones, Betty (Box 6)
    - Jones, Betty (Box 6)
      Personal correspondence
    - Jones, Bill T. (Box 6)
    - Joséph, Judy (Box 6)
    - Julliard Dance Ensemble (Box 6)
    - Kay Pepper Management (Box 6)
    - Kazuko Hillyer International Inc. (Box 6)
    - Kazuko Hillyer International Inc. (Box 6)
    - Kazuko Hillyer International Inc. (Box 6)
    - Keen, Elizabeth (Box 6)
    - Kei Takei (Box 6)
    - Kei Takei (Box 6)
    - Lamhut, Phyllis (Box 6)
    - Lamhut, Phyllis (Box 6)
    - Lang, Pearl (Box 6)
    - Lippincott, Gertrude (Box 6)
    - Lister, Merle (Box 6)
    - Lister, Merle (Box 6)
    - Lubovitch, Lar (Box 6)
    - Madison Dance Council (Box 6)
    - Maharaj, Birju (Box 6)
    - Matteo (Box 6)
    - Matthews/Napal Ltd. (Box 6)
    - McIntyre, Diane (Box 6)
    - Mid-America Ballet (Box 6)
    - Miller, Joan (Box 6)
    - Minnesota Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Missouri State Council on the Arts (Box 6)
    - Monk, Meredith (Box 6)
    - Monk, Meredith (Box 6)
    - Morgan and Maxwell (Box 6)
    - Morris, Mark (Box 6)
      Article
    - Miller, Jennifer (Box 6)
    - MultiGravitational Experiment Group (Box 6)
    - National Theatre Company (Box 6)
    - New Arts Management Inc. (Box 6)
    - New Haven Dance Ensemble (Box 6)
    - New School for Social Research (Box 6)
    - New York City Ballet (Box 6)
    - New York Dance Collective (Box 6)
    - Nicholas Brothers (Box 6)
    - North Carolina Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Ohman, Frank (Box 6)
    - Ormiston, Gale (Box 6)
    - Ormiston, Gale: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Oumansky, Valentina (Box 6)
    - Oved, Margalit (Box 6)
    - Oved, Margalit (Box 6)
    - Oved, Margalit (Box 6)
    - Page, Ruth (Box 6)
    - Perez, Rudy (Box 6)
    - Perez, Rudy: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Perron, Wendy (Box 6)
    - Phakavali (Box 6)
    - Pittsburgh Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Pomare, Eleo (Box 6)
    - Pomare, Eleo (Box 6)
    - Posin, Kathryn (Box 6)
    - Posin, Kathryn (Box 6)
    - Portland Dance Theater (Box 6)
    - Redlich, Don (Box 6)
    - Redlich, Don: Clippings (Box 6)
    - Rhode Island Dance Repertory Company (Box 6)
    - Richardson, Larry (Box 6)
    - Ririe-Woodbury Dance Company (Box 6)
    - Ririe-Woodbury: Publicity (Box 9)
    - Rogers, Rod (Box 6)
    - Rondo Dance Theater (Box 6)
    - Rozak, Loretto (Box 6)
    - Rivera, Luis (Box 6)
    - Sanasardo Dance Company (Box 6)
    - Sanasardo, Paul (Box 6)
    - Sanasardo, Paul (Box 6)
    - Sanasardo, Paul: Posters, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Savino, Jo (Box 6)
    - Schlamme, Martha (Box 6)
    - Shanta Rao, 1968 (Box 9)
      Newspaper article
    - Shawn, Ted (Box 6)
      Obituary
    - Shearer, Sybil (Box 6)
    - Shearer, Sybil (Box 6)
    - Sheldon Soffer Management Inc. (Box 6)
    - Sheldon Soffer Management Inc. (Box 6)
    - Solomons, Gus (Box 6)
    - Solomons, Gus (Box 6)
    - Sonic Arts Union (Box 6)
    - Spira (Box 6)
    - Stephen, Edith (Box 6)
    - Stephen, Edith (Box 6)
    - Synthetic Theatre (Box 6)
    - Tachibana, Sahomi (Box 6)
    - Terry, Walter (Box 6)
    - Tharp, Twyla (Box 6)
    - Tharp, Twyla (Box 6)
    - Tharp, Twyla (Box 6)
    - Torrance/Perrotta Management (Box 6)
    - University of Wisconsin (Box 6)
    - University of Wisconsin Festival of Contemporary Dance (Box 6)
    - Utah Repertory Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Utah Repertory Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Utah Repertory Dance Theatre (Box 6)
    - Van Dyke, Jan (Box 6)
    - Wagoner, Dan (Box 6)
    - Wagoner, Dan (Box 7)
    - Waring, James (Box 7)
    - James Waring at Judson: a Chronology, 1978 (Box 9)
      Program and publicity
    - Washington International Arts Letter (Box 7)
    - Weidman, Charles (Box 7)
    - Weidman, Charles (Box 7)
    - The Work Group (Box 7)
    - Wykell, Luise (Box 7)
    - Yass Hakoshima (Box 7)
    - Yuriko (Box 7)
    - Zimmermann, Gerda (Box 7)
- Personal Files, 1965-1984, undated, (1 Box)
  The Personal Files series is composed of the personal records of collection donor, Judith Sagan, and includes membership records from professional associations, unsorted press clippings, personal correspondence, and souvenir programs from non-Festival performances. It is arranged alphabetically by institution name and record type.
  - Association of American Dance Companies (Box 7)
    Membership records
  - Association of American Dance Companies (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies Nominating Committee, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Dance Companies, 1976-1978 (Box 7)
  - Association of Illinois Dance Companies (Box 7)
  - Association of Illinois Dance Companies (Box 7)
  - California Dance Directory (Box 7)
    Member directory
  - Chicago Alliance for the Performing Arts (Box 7)
  - Chicago Board of Governors: Mid-America Ballet (Box 7)
  - Chicago Dance Arts Coalition (Box 7)
  - Community Arts Foundation (Box 7)
  - Contemporary Concerts Inc. (Box 7)
  - Contemporary Concerts Inc. (Box 7)
  - Contemporary Concerts Inc. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Dance/America (Box 7)
  - Dance Book Forum (Box 7)
    Publication
  - Dance Gallery (Box 7)
    Newsletter
  - Dance in the Public School (Box 7)
  - Dance News (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Dance Notation Bureau, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - The Dance Paper, 1971 (Box 7)
  - The Dance Paper, 1971 (Box 7)
  - The Dance Paper, 1971 (Box 7)
  - The Dance Paper, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Economic Survival Glossary (Box 7)
  - Ford, Betty (Box 7)
  - Illinois Foundation for the Dance (Box 7)
  - International Dance Alliance (Box 7)
    Mailing
  - Jacob's Pillow, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Jacob's Pillow, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Joffrey, Robert, 1973 (Box 7)
    Autographed date book
  - Madison Dance Council (Box 7)
  - Manuscript (Box 7)
    Speech draft
  - National Association for Regional Ballet (Box 7)
  - National Association for Regional Ballet (Box 7)
  - The Subscription Revolution (Box 7)
  - MultiMedia Performing Arts (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1965, undated (Box 7)
    Programs
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Non-Festival Programs, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Partnership for the Arts (Box 7)
  - Unsorted Press (Box 7)
  - Unsorted Press (Box 7)
    Newspaper articles
  - Printed Materials, undated (Box 9)
    Non-Harper Theater Dance Festival publicity materials
  - Dance Paper, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Press Clippings: General Modern Dance History (Box 9)
  - Nijinsky / Pavlova: Posters, undated (Box 10)
    Non-Harper Theater Dance Festival posters from Joffrey Collection
- Photography, 1962-1992, undated, (1 Box)
  The Photography series is arranged alphabetically by company or performer name. Records include photographic prints, 35 mm slides, and negatives, largely provided by dance companies.
  - Unidentified Photos: Performance, undated (Box 4)
    Prints
  - Public Relations: Dance Gram Promotion, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Cunningham, James / Acme Dance Company, undated (Box 4)
  - Airaudo, Malon, undated (Box 4)
  - Ailey, Alvin, 1965, undated (Box 4)
  - Alba-Reyes Spanish Dance Company, 1965, undated (Box 4)
    Prints and negatives
  - Alum, Manuel, undated (Box 4)
  - American Mime Theatre, undated (Box 4)
  - Boston Ballet, undated (Box 4)
  - Chamber Ballet, undated (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Ze'eva, undated (Box 4)
  - Cunningham, Merce / Cage, John / Tudor, David, 1965-1975, undated (Box 4)
  - Jarsolow, Risa / Perron, Wendy, undated (Box 4)
  - Farber, Viola, 1972, undated (Box 4)
  - Falco, Louis, 1969-1970, undated (Box 4)
  - Goslar, Lotte, 1966, undated (Box 4)
  - Hawkins, Erick / Dlugoszewski, Lucia, undated (Box 4)
  - Janislawski, Mimi, undated (Box 4)
  - Lewitzky, Bella, 1973, undated (Box 4)
  - Limón, José / José Limón Dance Company, undated (Box 4)
  - Louis, Murray, undated (Box 4)
  - Louis, Murray, undated (Box 4)
    Prints, 35mm slides, contact sheet
  - Nagrin, Daniel, undated (Box 4)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, undated (Box 4)
  - Nikolais, Alwin, undated (Box 4)
    Prints, 35mm slides
  - Oved, Margalit, undated (Box 4)
  - Pennsylvania Ballet Company, 1966, undated (Box 4)
  - Pilobolus Dance Theatre, undated (Box 4)
  - Ormiston, Gale, undated (Box 4)
  - Posin, Kathryn, undated (Box 4)
  - Redlich, Don, undated (Box 4)
  - Richardson, Larry, undated (Box 4)
  - Taylor, Paul, 1962-1978, undated (Box 4)
  - Tetley, Glen, undated (Box 4)
  - Villella, Edward, undated (Box 4)